Guide to the Records of the Tisch School of the Arts Department of Photography and Imaging RG.35.5
New York University Archives
Records of the Tisch School of the Arts Department of Photography and Imaging
1984-2019
New York University Archives
Tisch School of the Arts. Department of Photography and Imaging
RG.35.5
22 linear feet in 16 record cartons, 9 manuscript boxes, 2 half manuscript box, 1 oversize flat box
442 videocassettes (vhs)
114 videocassettes (hi8)
49 audiocassettes
5 minidvs
4 videocassettes (betacam)
1 videocassettes (u-matic)
336.47 Gigabytes
The Department of Photography and Imaging at the NYU Tisch School of the Arts is a four-year BFA program focused on the making and understanding of images through an arts curriculum grounded in liberal arts education. Students and faculty in the department work in varied modes of analog and digital photo-based image making and multimedia. This collection consists of materials created and collected by the Department of Photography and Imaging at the NYU Tisch School of the Arts from the late 1980s through the 2010s, and includes catalogs, programs from exhibitions, and copies of ISO magazine. The collection also includes audio and video recordings in both analog and electronic format of the department's events, guest lectures, and panel sessions, as well as examples the department's film library of commercial releases.
Scope and Contents
This collection consists of materials created and collected by the Department of Photography and Imaging at the NYU Tisch School of the Arts from the late 1980s through the 2010s, and includes catalogs, programs from exhibitions, and copies of ISO magazine. The collection also includes audio and video recordings in both analog and electronic format of the department's events, guest lectures, and panel sessions, as well as examples the department's film library of commercial releases.
Arrangement
This collection has not been arranged by an archivist. The materials are arranged in the order in which they were received from the donor.
Historical Note
The Department of Photography and Imaging at the NYU Tisch School of the Arts is a four-year BFA program focused on the making and understanding of images through an arts curriculum grounded in liberal arts education. Students and faculty in the department work in varied modes of analog and digital photo-based image making and multimedia.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open without restrictions.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Transferred by Tisch School of the Arts Department of Photography and Imaging in September 2017; the accession number associated with this transfer is 2019.037. Accretions were transferred in November 2019; the accession numbers associated with these transfers are 2019.120 and 2019.121.
Audiovisual Access Policies and Procedures
Audiovisual materials have not been preserved and may not be available to researchers. Materials not yet digitized will need to have access copies made before they can be used. To request an access copy, or if you are unsure if an item has been digitized, please contact [repository name, special.collections@nyu.edu, 212-998-2596] with the collection name, collection number, and a description of the item(s) requested. A staff member will respond to you with further information.
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
Advance notice is required for the use of computer records. Original physical digital media is restricted. Born-digital materials have not been transferred and may not be available to researchers. Researchers may request access copies. To request that material be transferred, or if you are unsure if material has been transferred, please contact University Archives, special.collections@nyu.edu, 212-998-2596] with the collection name, collection number, and a description of the item(s) requested. A staff member will respond to you with further information.
Photography -- Periodicals; Photography -- Study and teaching; Exhibition catalogs.; Tisch School of the Arts; Tisch School of the Arts. Department of Photography and Imaging
- Department of Photography and Imaging: Catalogs, 1999-2017 (Box 1, Box 2, Box 3, Box 4)
- Department of Photography and Imaging: ISO Magazine, 2010-2017 (Box 3)
- Video Recordings, 1984-2000 (Box 5)
- Video Recordings, 1993-2000 (Box 6, Box 21)
- Video Recordings, 1991-2000 (Box 7, Box 23)
- Video Recordings, 1995-2001 (Box 8, Box 28)
- Video Recordings, 1994-2004 (Box 9, Box 26)
- Video Recordings, 1991-2004 (Box 10, Box 27)
- Video Recordings, 1999-2005 (Box 11)
- Video Recordings, 1992-1996 (Box 12, Box 24)
- Video Recordings, 1991-1992 (Box 13, Box 25)
- Video Recordings, 1985-1991 (Box 14)
- Video Recordings, 1992-1999 (Box 15)
- Video Recordings, 1986-1997 (Box 16)
- Video Recordings, 1985-1990 (Box 17)
- Video Recordings, 1984-2005 (Box 18)
- Video and Audio Recordings, 1984-2005 (Box 19)
- Commercial DVDs, 1984-2005 (Box 20)
- Commercial CDs, Optical Discs, Zip Disks, 1984-2005 (Box Shared University Archives Accessions 003, Box Shared University Archives 136)
- Publications, 1997-2019 (Box 22)